builtinchicago.org 2019-05-16

# Privacy Policy | Built In Chicago

Last Updated: 2/21/18

Your privacy is important to us.  Built In, Inc. and its subsidiaries and affiliates (“Built In,” “we,” or “us”), understand your concerns with regard to how information about you is used and shared, and we appreciate your trust that we will use and share information about you carefully and sensibly. This Privacy Policy describes what information we collect about you, how we collect it, how we use it, with whom we may share it, and what choices you have regarding it. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and is a part of the [Terms of Use](http://www.builtinchicago.org/terms-use) of our Website (the “Site”).  The services provided on the Site are referred to as “Services”. We encourage you to become familiar with this Privacy Policy and our [Terms of Use](http://www.builtinchicago.org/terms-use). By accessing and using the Site, you agree that you have read and understand this Privacy Policy and that you accept and consent to the privacy practices (and any uses and disclosures of information about you) that are described in this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy may change from time to time. Your continued use of the Site after we make changes is deemed to be acceptance of those changes, so please check the Privacy Policy periodically for updates.

This Privacy Policy applies only to information collected at this Site. It does not apply to any other websites.  For instance, if you click “Apply Now” on a job posting on the Site, we may redirect you to such employer’s career site to submit a resume or application.  Information collected through such third party sites is not subject to this Privacy Policy, but instead is subject to such third party service provider’s privacy policy.  We encourage you to seek out and read the privacy policy of each website that you visit.

1\.    What information do we collect, and how do we collect it?

We refer to information that can personally identify you, such as your name, address and email address as “Personal Information”. While you may browse the Site without providing Personal Information, when you create an account and otherwise use the Services, you will provide certain Personal Information, such as your name, email address, username and password, work and educational history, and other information that populates your online profile.  We and our third party service providers (“Contractors”) may use the Personal Information you provide to us to search for publicly available information (such as your business expertise, skills, current and past job titles, education, activity on other publicly available websites, and your city location) to create an enhanced profile that is available on the Site to a limited number of users. If you choose to login to the Site with a third-party social media site such as Facebook or Google, we may collect Personal Information from such third party social media site, in which case we will ask for your consent prior to your logging in to the Site using your social media account.

We use your Personal Information to provide the Site and Services to you, including, but not limited to maintaining your profile page, supplementing your profile page with publicly available information, contacting you to deliver information that we believe is targeted to your interests, informing you of any relevant job postings that may be of interest to you based upon your expressed interests and Usage Information related to you, to manage your participation in events, and to otherwise provide any additional and new services that may be of interest to you. Except as specifically stated in this Privacy Policy, we do not disclose your Personal Information to third parties.   

Additionally, we may collect and display information that does not personally identify you. This includes, but is not limited to, information about general industry trends, job availability and skills needed for these jobs, salary trends, and other information related to job seeking, recruiting and branding, all of which are provided to best deliver Services to you (“Aggregate Information”).

As with many other websites, Built In and its Contractors may also collect certain non-personal statistical information pertaining to you and the equipment and communications method that you use to access the Internet and our Site. We refer to this information as “Usage Information”.  This Usage Information allows us to optimize the Site to the Internet connections and equipment that are used to visit the Site. For instance, in order to make the Site better, we may collect information on: how long you use the Site; which links you click on the Site; whether you have used the Site before and on how many occasions; how frequently you use the Site; and at which point you exit the Site. We collect this information directly from you when you provide it to us and automatically as you navigate through and interact with our Site. Information collected this way includes: (i) details of your visits to our Site, including traffic data, location data, logs, other communication data, and the resources that you access and use on the Site; and (ii) information about your computer and internet connection, including your IP address, operating system, and browser type. The technologies we use for this automatic data collection of usage information may include:

•    Cookies (or browser cookies): A cookie is a small file placed on the hard drive of your computer. We use session cookies to keep track of your login information.  You may refuse to accept browser cookies by activating the appropriate setting on your browser. However, if you select this setting, you may be unable to access certain parts of our Site. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you use the Site.

•    Pixel Tags / Web Beacons: Pages of our website and our emails may contain small electronic files known as web beacons (also referred to as clear gifs. pixel tags and single-pixel gifs) that permit us, for example, to count users who have visited those pages or opened an email. We may also use these web beacons for other related Site statistics (e.g., recording the popularity of certain content and verifying system and server integrity). For example, you may receive targeted notifications of available job postings based on the content or the pages you click on.

•    Device identifiers:  When you use a mobile device like a tablet or phone to access our Site, we may access, collect, monitor, store on your device, and/or remotely store one or more “device identifiers”. Device identifiers are small data files or similar data structures stored on or associated with your mobile device, which uniquely identify your mobile device. A device identifier may be data stored in connection with the device hardware, data stored in connection with the device’s operating system or other software, or data sent to the device by us.

2\.    How will we use the information you provide to us?

In addition to the uses described above or in our [Terms of Use](http://www.builtinchicago.org/terms-use), we and our Contractors may use the information that we collect from or about you to analyze and improve the content, materials, and Services that we make available on the Site, to notify you of changes made to the Site, to evaluate user needs and customize the Site content delivered to you according to those needs, to send you promotional materials that you request from us, and for other legitimate and lawful business purposes. If you contact us for support or assistance, we may use information about you or your system that you provide or that we collect for purposes such as verifying whether your system meets the minimum requirements needed to use the Site and our various Services.

We and our Contractors may store Personal Information for as long as needed for the purposes indicated in this Privacy Policy, which may be indefinitely. We and our Contractors may store Personal Information in the United States, or we may transfer it to other countries.

3\. Contractors

We use Contractors in order to efficiently provide our Site to you. Some Contractors, such as credit card processing companies, will collect information directly from you and provide us with relevant data. We may use this information to carry out our obligations and enforce our rights arising from any contracts entered into (for instance, to collect any authorized fees). Information collected from Contractors are governed by their privacy policies. You should view the privacy policies of Contractors before providing information to them. If you interact with a third party, the Contractor may have access to your Personal Information, even though we do not disclose your Personal Information for these purposes without your consent.

4\.    With whom do we share the information we collect?  

We may disclose Usage Information and Aggregate Information about our users without restriction. This information cannot be used to personally identify our users. If we combine the Usage Information and Aggregate Information with your Personal Information (for instance, to send targeted job postings to you based on your usage of the Site), it will be considered Personal Information.  We may share Personal Information with our Contractors and affiliates in order to provide Services to you, and for other lawful business reasons. We do not disclose your Personal Information except in the circumstances described here:

•    To Provide the Services:  We may share or disclose your Personal Information, at your direction, in connection with your use of the Site and our providing Services to our users.  Unless you opt out, we share Personal Information about you that we collect from you or third party sources with some of our corporate Members that purchase premium memberships (“Premium Members”) and Contractors in connection with our job search and recruiting services.   Additionally, your profile information will be included in a searchable database for Premium Members and other users of our Service to view. We may also provide such users and Premium Members with information on users of the Site that visit their company page or otherwise click the “Apply Now” button on a job posting to be redirected to such Premium Member’s site. Premium Members can export limited information from your profile, such as your name, title and email address. You should be aware that these parties may contact you, and that this may result in unsolicited messages from third parties.   

•    Contractors:  We may share your Personal Information with or disclose it to Contractors and other third parties we use to support our business.  For example, we may decide from time to time to utilize a number of business and marketing partners in delivering the content, materials, and Services available on or through the Site to you. We may share Personal Information with these business and marketing partners for any lawful purpose, including to communicate with you or to fulfill your requests for our Services. Built In and its Contractors may also produce reports on Site traffic or usage patterns and share these reports with our business and marketing partners and others.

•    Business Transfers:  In the event that Built In is involved in a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution, or other sale or transfer of some or all of our assets, whether as a going concern or as part of bankruptcy, liquidation, or similar proceeding, your Personal Information held by us may be among the assets transferred.

•    Law and Harm:  Notwithstanding anything to the contrary in this Privacy Policy, we may disclose or share your Personal Information in order to comply with any court order, law, or legal process, including to respond to any government or regulatory request, or if we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to protect the rights, property, or safety of Built In, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

•    Enforcement: We may also use and disclose Personal Information about you to establish or exercise our legal rights, to enforce the Terms of Use, to assert and defend against legal claims, or if we believe such disclosure is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take other action regarding actual or suspected illegal or fraudulent activities or potential threats to the physical safety or well-being of any person.

•    Disclosed when Collected or With Your Consent:  For any other purpose disclosed by us when you provide the information or otherwise with your consent.

4\.    What choices do you have?

When corresponding with Built In or our representatives, or when making a request for information or otherwise interacting with us or others through the Site, you choose what information to supply, what questions or comments to submit, whether you wish to receive further information, and by what method of communication such information should be delivered. Please take care to share only such information as is needed or that you believe is appropriate. You are under no obligation to provide us with personally identifiable information, but without it we may not be able to provide you the products or services you request. We have created mechanisms to provide you with the following control over your information:  

•    Tracking Technologies: You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that many parts of the Site may then be inaccessible or will not function properly.

•    Email Communications: If you do not wish to have your email address used by Built In to promote our own services or third parties, you may select the kinds of promotional messages you will receive by modifying your account settings. You may also opt out of receiving these messages by following the “unsubscribe” link contained within the promotional message. For example, you will be asked if you are open to new job opportunities.  If you select yes, we may contact you with employer requests for introduction, which you may accept or reject.  Alternatively, you have the option to decline to receive introduction requests from employers. You will also have the option to opt out of these messages by indicating you are not open to new opportunities, and you have the option to reject introductions to employers through the Site.

•    Job Seeker Database: When you create an account on the Site, you will automatically be listed on Built In’s database of job seekers which can be accessed and searched by Premium Members and employers. If you do not wish to be listed on this database, you may opt out of being listed on the database.

•    Opt Out.  You may opt out of the sharing described in this Privacy Policy by sending an email to support@builtin.com.

•    Delete Your Account.  You may delete your account by emailing us at support@builtin.com.  Please be advised that, even if we successfully delete your account, employers who have paid for our databases and Premium Members may have retained a copy of your Personal Information for their own files. We cannot control the retention or use of your Personal Information once they have been downloaded by third parties, and you will not be able to delete information held by those third parties.

You may contact us as indicated below if at any time you would like to ask us about our data collection practices and our information security policy.

California Privacy Rights

California Civil Code Section §1798.83 permits users that are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of Personal Information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an email to support@builtin.com.

5\.    How Do We Protect Information Collected About You? 

Built In and our Contractors take commercially reasonable measures to protect against the loss, misuse and unauthorized access or disclosure, alteration and destruction of your personal data by aiming to maintain appropriate physical, procedural and electronic safeguards to protect your personal data, including:

•    Restricting access to personal data to our employees and Contractors on a “need to know” basis;

•    Enforcing policies and procedures for our employees in their handling of personal data; and;

•    Using technologies designed to safeguard data during its transmission, such as SSL encryption for the data you provide on our websites.

The safety and security of your information also depends on you. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password for access to certain parts of our Site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share your password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we do our best to protect your Personal Information, we cannot guarantee the security of your Personal Information transmitted to our Site. Any transmission of Personal Information is at your own risk and we do not guarantee that information that you transmit or otherwise supply to us, or any communications conducted on or through the Site, is or will be totally secure. We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained on the Site. If you become aware of any breach of Site security, this Privacy Policy, or the [Terms of Use](http://www.builtinchicago.org/terms-use), please notify us immediately.

6\.  Children under Age 13

Our Site is not intended for children under 13 years of age. No one under age 13 may provide any Personal Information on the Site. We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under 13. If you are under 13, do not use or provide any information on the Site. If we learn we have collected or received Personal Information from a child under 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at support@builtin.com.

7\.    We may change this Notice.

From time to time, we may change our privacy practices, and this Privacy Policy, because of changes in relevant and applicable legal or regulatory requirements, in our business or our business practices, or in our attempts to better serve your needs and those of our other members. Notice of such changes to our privacy practices will be given in the manner described in the [Terms of Use](http://www.builtinchicago.org/terms-use) and a revised Privacy Policy will be posted on the Site.  The date of the most recent revision to the policy is identified herein.  You are responsible for periodically reviewing this Privacy Policy to check for changes.

7\.    Any questions? Please contact us at:

Built In, Inc.

440 North Wells Suite 502

Chicago, Illinois 60654

Telephone: 312-476-8478

Email: support@builtin.com

Acknowledgement

BY ACCESSING OR USING THE SITE, YOU ACKNOWLEDGE THAT YOU HAVE READ, UNDERSTAND, AND CONSENT TO OUR PRIVACY PRACTICES AND TO THE USES AND DISCLOSURES OF INFORMATION THAT WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU, AND YOU AGREE TO BE BOUND BY THE [TERMS OF USE](http://www.builtinchicago.org/terms-use) APPLICABLE TO YOU.
